<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title></title><link href="http://thegodsproject.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://thegodsproject.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://thegodsproject.com/</id><updated>2016-10-27T22:30:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Tung Lin Kok Yuen</title><link href="http://thegodsproject.com/tung-lin-kok-yuen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-27T22:30:00+08:00</published><author><name>the god(s) project</name></author><id>tag:thegodsproject.com,2016-10-27:tung-lin-kok-yuen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Episode 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up on a slope in Happy Valley, Tung Lin Kok Yuen carries its own particular piece of Hong Kong history. We talk to two people on their journey to enlightenment, and what this means for them in the day to day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click &lt;a href="http://programme.rthk.hk/channel/radio/programme.php?name=dab31/p0225_the_gods_project&amp;amp;d=2016-10-13&amp;amp;p=7395&amp;amp;e=381314&amp;amp;m=episode"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to listen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tung Lin Kok Yuen is an extraordinary commemoration of a 50th wedding anniversary, but beyond its unique architecture, the family behind it captures so forcefully the intersection of government, economy and society of a particular moment.  I’d heard about the Hotung name in passing, of course, usually in association with squabbles over land or money, but it wasn’t until I started reading about its patriarch did I realize how much his existence shed light on attitudes that are still very much present today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been obsessed with Sir Robert Hotung for about a month now.  Here’s someone who, essentially from birth, had to navigate the boundaries and perceptions of two communities that were far from eager to invite him into the fold.  His Dutch father, who had moved to Hong Kong to work at a firm that shipped goods and coolies between China and San Francisco, took on a protected woman, named Sze Tai.  When Robert was around 7, Bosman was declared bankrupt and moved away from the colony, leaving behind Madame Sze and her children.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was dire if a foreign father up and left, as oftentimes the whole family would have been dependent on him to survive.  The European community didn’t hide its disdain for the custom of taking on protected women.  Meanwhile, Chinese kin groups were unlikely to accept Eurasian children as it was often the mother who was Chinese, not the father, and patriarchy was/is very much alive.  They were a group apart, marginalized by both - but despite the upheaval, Sir Robert excelled at his studies and worked his way up to the head of the compradore department at Jardines, and was believed to be one of the richest men in Hong Kong by the age of 35.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colonialism being colonialism, a land ordinance was passed in 1904, preventing houses on the Peak to be let to the Chinese.  Sir Robert bought a house in the district two years later.  He was lambasted as an “illegitimate half-caste whose wives and Concubines numbered four” by the governor at the time, white families refused to let their children play with his, and more than a decade later, when he owned three houses on the Peak, the next governor, Sir Francis May, wrote in 1917 that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Chinese families if resident in the Peak District would have much more frequent and closer communication with the Chinese portion of Victoria than do Europeans and the chance of the carriage and dissemination of communicable disease would be much increased…It would be little short of a calamity if an alien and, by European standards, a semi-civilized race were allowed to drive the white man from the one area in Hong Kong, in which he can live with his wife and children in a white man’s healthy surroundings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many articles on the Hotung family remark on his Chineseness - and to what end?  That it was remarkable that someone half white could speak Cantonese, preferred to wear the gown of a Chinese scholar, exhibited filial piety and raised his family on Confucian values?  There is always a desire to make sense of things by apportioning his selves, put them on a scale and see where it tips.  But it’s also a feeling that hasn’t quite died out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re no longer a colony.  Chinese people can live on the Peak.  But the notions of being measured up to a moving goal post of authentic Hong Kongness is certainly still there, always dependent on who’s doing the measuring.  Despite our Asia’s World City, East meets West slogans, there are still plenty of opinions on who does or doesn’t belong in Hong Kong.  Lines are still drawn in everyday attitudes - “expats” and “locals” identify themselves using those labels, people who may have been born and raised in our city but aren’t ethnically Chinese are still asked where they’re really from, and I, who have grown up here but may stumble over Cantonese, get the raised eyebrow on occasion when I try to claim my place as a Hong Konger.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose that’s why Buddhism is so intriguing - the concept of having no self seems antithetical to everything we hear about the importance of having an identity, something you can build and hold onto.  All the talk we hear about what makes one qualify as a Hong Konger, how that self can be justified, is no longer rooted when we recognize that these themselves are not eternal and permanent.  The question that remains is how we might be able to live better together when we’re aware of that - when we take it to be true - how unflinching awareness can potentially bring us closer in community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Am A Man Who Will Fight For Your Honor by Chris Zabriskie&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href="http://chriszabriskie.com/honor/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://chriszabriskie.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Ammar Mosque</title><link href="http://thegodsproject.com/ammar-mosque.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-20T22:10:00+08:00</published><author><name>the god(s) project</name></author><id>tag:thegodsproject.com,2016-10-20:ammar-mosque.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Episode 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a quiet, tree-lined street just steps away from Wan Chai Road, Ammar Mosque is home to one of the most bustling halal dim sum restaurants in the city.  We listen to the stories of four people who've strengthened their faith in Islam in Hong Kong, by way of France, Indonesia, Pakistan and Tunisia.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click &lt;a href="http://programme.rthk.hk/channel/radio/programme.php?name=dab31/p0225_the_gods_project&amp;amp;d=2016-10-13&amp;amp;p=7395&amp;amp;e=381314&amp;amp;m=episode"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to listen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when I start sketching out an episode, what takes up all the mindspace is a list of what &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to do.  While very much aware of the anti-Islam rhetoric that’s captured the rest of the world, I didn’t want to counter each misinformed point with a listicle of soundbites (“Islam is not violent,” “Not all Muslims are oppressed”), which would force the conversation to take place on a single plane.  I didn’t want my interviewees to feel like they had to bear the burden of defending their faith.  I didn’t want to present Islam as some faraway other to the tune of harmonic minor scales, nor did I want Islam to be made palatable by solely taking on the vocabulary of faith that other religions might draw upon, that the audience might be more familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a question underlying it all: at the end of the day, how do you humanize?  If providing the facts only goes so far in erasing misconceptions, how do you actually help others see people as fully formed, fully fleshed out human beings?  Part of me (the plan-making self, that wishes mindset change could be corralled and implemented through a series of steps) wonders if it can all happen at the same time.  It’s impossible to laser blast away all stereotypes in a single episode, in the style of those well-loved Buzzfeed explainer videos.  And though these are important in refuting ignorance, there also needs to be space where people are permitted to be people, where they can be seen as people first and foremost - not as defenders, or educators, or even instructors who can help you sound informed during dinners with uninformed relatives.  What was fascinating was the chance to delve into specific parts of each person’s turning point with Islam and how that is influenced by their own, very particular circumstance.  Everyone had varying degrees of interaction with Islam before they decided to fully commit themselves, and it’s this moment that captivates me the most - the places they had to spend time in, whether internally or externally, before they were spurred on to explore the depths of faith.  It was inevitable; it made sense.  And with this group - an Indonesian caregiver and volunteer, a Hong Kong-raised university student studying psychology, a French banker coming to terms with capitalism and a Tunisian professor with a love of linguistics - I sought to learn about their contexts, and they were extremely generous with their time and words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cylinder Six by Chris Zabriskie&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href="http://chriszabriskie.com/cylinders/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://chriszabriskie.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accralate - The Dark Contenent by Kevin MacLeod&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href="http://incompetech.com/music/royalty-free/index.html?isrc=USUAN1100341"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://incompetech.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deliberate Thought by Kevin MacLeod&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href="http://incompetech.com/music/royalty-free/?keywords=deliberate+thought"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://incompetech.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sun is Scheduled to Come Out Tomorrow by Chris Zabriskie&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href="http://chriszabriskie.com/honor/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://chriszabriskie.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Our Lady of Mt. Carmel</title><link href="http://thegodsproject.com/our-lady.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-13T09:25:00+08:00</published><author><name>the god(s) project</name></author><id>tag:thegodsproject.com,2016-10-13:our-lady.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Episode 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canossians, Carmelites and the calling - a conversation with a recently returned sister, who followed in the footsteps of Italian nuns in Hong Kong over 150 years ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click &lt;a href="http://programme.rthk.hk/channel/radio/programme.php?name=dab31/p0225_the_gods_project&amp;amp;d=2016-10-13&amp;amp;p=7395&amp;amp;e=381314&amp;amp;m=episode"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to listen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up in a Protestant family, I often felt that Catholicism was the strict older aunt - you could see how you’re related, but you also know that she’s got a way about her, a set of staunch principles and schedules she lives by, a perspective that will set you straight.  Contemporary non-denominational services had always been easier to grasp with their pop-inflected hymns, direct testimonies and conversational preaching, while Catholicism seemed to be where you would get the stick, the commandments, the do’s and don’ts.  I carried this with me for a while - that Catholicism was the type of Christianity for grown-ups, who could better appreciate the ritual and liturgy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d never been to Sunday Mass until the recording of this episode at Our Lady of Mount Carmel Church, on Star Street in Wanchai.  There’s something about witnessing a service that shares a similar foundation, but is remarkably different from the faith you’ve grown up practicing.  It makes you try to pinpoint what it is that you find spiritual or holy, when you seek to tease it apart from pure ‘feeling’, and attempt to identify what the new practice is imparting upon you.  Standing there in the crowd, I felt that Catholicism was illuminating a contemplative thread of Christianity.  I’d once had the privilege of staying at a Benedictine monastery, and it was ironically a whirlwind to keep up - waking at 5:30am everyday, attending six or seven prayers, bowing and kneeling and sitting during all the wrong moments, wrangling my tongue around Gregorian chants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When everything feels foreign, a space opens up, and you have the opportunity to imbue that space with intentional meaning.  Definitions of what something is supposed to signify or invoke within you haven’t been set yet, and it allows for an expansion of your understanding in a world where boundaries and forms are more fluid.  For me, there was a power to the silence that made itself present - not as a pause, or a breath, but as an existence that carries weight - something I had never known I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enzo Bianchi, who founded the Monastic Community of Bose, wrote that “interior silence makes us capable of listening intelligently, speaking with discretion and discerning what burns in the heart of another.”  The way that Sister Maria Hsu carries herself reminds me of this - and through that reflection, she is able to serve her communities in the ways that they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Light Awash by Kevin MacLeod&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href="http://incompetech.com/music/royalty-free/index.html?isrc=USUAN1100175"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://incompetech.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heliograph by Chris Zabriskie&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href="http://chriszabriskie.com/divider/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://chriszabriskie.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meditation Impromptu 01 by Kevin MacLeod&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href="http://incompetech.com/music/royalty-free/index.html?isrc=USUAN1100163"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://incompetech.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>welcome</title><link href="http://thegodsproject.com/welcome.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-13T08:30:00+08:00</published><author><name>the god(s) project</name></author><id>tag:thegodsproject.com,2016-10-13:welcome.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;origin story&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the god(s) project.  Let’s start with 3 things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong ranks as one of the top 10 most religiously diverse places in the world.  Religious freedom is our fundamental right under the Basic Law, and it’s one of the reasons why various faith communities in Hong Kong continue to thrive.  In a time when that right isn’t universally upheld or respected, it becomes even more crucial to remember that this is something of immense importance, that cannot be compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But aside from daily passing a temple, shrine, mosque or church, there are few opportunities to hear about the real, human experiences that are nestled in those spaces.  Each faith holds a story about its arrival on the shores of our city, but it also carries millions of memories within each believer as they learn to chart their path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to explore how these memories weave into a texture of faith - the kind of faith that encourages you to live your life larger, in more expansive, more infinite ways.  I want to know what it looks like, feels like and invokes in each person across different spiritualities.  The faith vs. reason dichotomy has always seemed too easy, and the explanations of faith as a feeling or instinct haven’t felt complete either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also know that the motivation behind creating the god(s) project is somewhat selfish in nature.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seeds were planted in an ocean of Post-Its one evening, in a tenuous attempt to map out the pockets that could create or shape meaning in life.  I had returned to Hong Kong from working overseas the year before, and even though I was already nine months into the city I called home, everything still felt uncertain and in flux.  As I categorized the Post-Its by importance, faith/spirituality floated to the top and decided to stay there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t too surprising.  I had attended Alpha (a crash course on Christianity) twice, was taking tours at mosques, sitting in on Quaker meetings and listening to songs at a Baha’i gathering.  They were all ways of trying to get at why people carved out time in their already frenetic Hong Kong lives to devote to something that didn’t seem to provide immediate tangible benefits - and I wanted to know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s this ongoing life-sorting process, as well as a total obsession with people’s stories in faith, that has spurred the creation of the god(s) project.  I’m not trying to draw any big, grand conclusions about religion here; rather, it’s a small window into someone’s particular experience, wrapped up in a love letter to Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy it.  And I’m looking forward to hearing what you think.  Huge thanks to Tegan Smyth and Kenji Morimoto for all their researching help and support through it all.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>